Guide to the Gerald Stern Papers, 1920s-2012 SC.2007.04
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- General Activities, 1948-2005; VII.
  - 2015 Addition, 2003-2012
    - Application letter for poetry retreat on the Isle of Jura, 2007 (Box 54, Folder 8)
    - Association of Writers and Writing Programs tribute to Stern, 2008-2009 (Box 54, Folder 9)
    - Autumn House royalty statements and brochures, 2004-2009 (Box 54, Folder 10)
    - Auden Notes at Swarthmore (Box 54, Folder 11)
    - Articles about Gerald Stern, 2006-2009 (Box 54, Folder 12)
    - American Academy of Arts and Letters Award of Merit, 2010 (Box 54, Folder 13)
    - "Apologia Pro Sua Pranta" (Box 54, Folder 14)
    - Best American Poetry Selections, 2006-2011 (Box 54, Folder 15)
    - Blue Flower Arts Agency agreements, correspondents, and events, 2006-2009 (Box 54, Folder 16)
    - Christina Buss, 2009 (Box 54, Folder 17)
    - Contract for Bullet in My Neck, 2009 (Box 54, Folder 18)
    - Book dealers (Box 54, Folder 19)
    - Bryn Mawr poetry class, 2009 (Box 54, Folder 20)
    - Carnegie Mellon University Press, 2001-2009 (Box 54, Folder 21)
    - Cave Canem Benefit, 2010 (Box 54, Folder 22)
    - Cavan Berry Press, 2006-2009 (Box 54, Folder 23)
    - Chapbook Festival, 2012 (Box 54, Folder 24)
    - City of Asylum Pittsburgh, 2008 (Box 54, Folder 25)
    - College of New Jersey, 2006 (Box 54, Folder 26)
    - Comments on "Spring," published in The New Yorker, 2008 (Box 54, Folder 27)
    - Cortland Review feature, 2008-2010 (Box 54, Folder 28)
    - Cultural Center of Cape Cod Judging, 2011 (Box 54, Folder 29)
    - Deborah Diggs memorial, 2009-2011 (Box 54, Folder 30)
    - Drew University commencement speech, 2009 (Box 54, Folder 31)
    - Drew University Poet in residence, 2008-2009 (Box 54, Folder 32)
    - Enid Stover Poetry Recitation, 2009 (Box 54, Folder 33)
    - Ed Ochester reading, University of Pittsburgh, 2007 (Box 54, Folder 34)
    - Fishouse Poems Audio Archive, 2006-2009 (Box 54, Folder 35)
    - Fishouse "Gold in the Ore" Anthology, 2007-2008 (Box 54, Folder 36-37)
    - Folger Shakespeare Library Event, 2008 (Box 54, Folder 38)
    - Gerald Stern Foundation proposal, 2006 (Box 54, Folder 39)
    - Glasgow Anthology request, 2012 (Box 54, Folder 40)
    - Jacob Adler Book, 2009 (Box 54, Folder 41)
    - Jewish Book Awards Program, 2006-2012 (Box 54, Folder 42)
    - "Job: the Open Book" (Box 54, Folder 43)
    - John Simon Guggenheim Memorial Foundation Fellowship, 2009-2010 (Box 54, Folder 44)
    - John Simon Guggenheim Memorial Foundation Fellowship, 2008-2009 (Box 54, Folder 45)
    - John Simon Guggenheim Memorial Foundation Fellowship, 2007-2009 (Box 54, Folder 46)
    - Hofstra students (Box 54, Folder 47)
    - Impeach Cheney statement written for demonstration, 2007 (Box 54, Folder 48)
    - Intimacy and Sexuality lecture (Box 54, Folder 49)
    - Irving Greenburg article (Box 54, Folder 50)
    - Isles, community development organization, 2007 (Box 54, Folder 51)
    - Jackson Poetry Prize judging, 2010-2011 (Box 54, Folder 52)
    - Jeff Streeby paper on Stern Poems, 2008 (Box 54, Folder 53)
    - Kathleen Fagley's Linebreak Lecture, 2005 (Box 54, Folder 54)
    - Leaves of Grass Film Project, 2004 (Box 54, Folder 55)
    - Library of Congress Poetry and Literature Center's The Poetry of American Identity Project, 2012 (Box 54, Folder 56)
    - Lucille Clifton tributes, 2010 (Box 54, Folder 57)
    - Lucky Life movie, 2010 (Box 54, Folder 58)
    - Lampert, Norbert concerning documentary, "Poets and Poetry in the US Today", 2007 (Box 54, Folder 59)
    - Lyrikling, 2007 (Box 54, Folder 60)
    - MacDowell Colony Residency, 2010-2011 (Box 54, Folder 61)
    - New England College, 2005-2006 (Box 54, Folder 62)
    - New England College, 2007-2008 (Box 54, Folder 63)
    - New Jersey State Museum, "Vision and a Voice", 2005 (Box 54, Folder 64)
    - New York Times article on Stern, 2003 (Box 54, Folder 65)
    - New Yorker submissions, 2006-2011 (Box 54, Folder 66)
    - Norton royalty statements, 2005-2010 (Box 54, Folder 67)
    - Norton correspondence and agreements, 2003-2010 (Box 54, Folder 68)
    - The Oxford Project, 2008 (Box 55, Folder 1)
    - Paterson Award for Sustained Literary Achievement, 2006 (Box 55, Folder 2)
    - Ploughshares Cohen Awards nominations, 2008-2009 (Box 55, Folder 3)
    - Poems rejected by Jerry (Box 55, Folder 4)
    - "The Poem That Changed My Life", for American Poet, 2011 (Box 55, Folder 5)
    - Poets House, 2007-2011 (Box 55, Folder 6)
    - Poets and poetry quotes (Box 55, Folder 7)
    - Poetry Foundation's bio on Gerald Stern, 2012 (Box 55, Folder 8)
    - Poetry on Posters Project, 2010 (Box 55, Folder 9)
    - Poetry Society contest judge, 2011 (Box 55, Folder 10)
    - Prague - Romantic Talk (Box 55, Folder 11)
    - The Preacher - APR's Publication (Box 55, Folder 12)
    - The Preacher, Georgia Review, 2007 (Box 55, Folder 13)
    - The Preacher - Letters About, 2007 (Box 55, Folder 14)
    - Prose explanation of poetry (Box 55, Folder 15)
    - Poetry Society of America Awards, 2006 (Box 55, Folder 16)
    - Provincetown Fine Arts Work Center, 2005 (Box 55, Folder 17)
    - Pushcart Prize, 2007-2011 (Box 55, Folder 18)
    - Research (Box 55, Folder 19-21)
    - Research and statements for Jewish Encyclopedia, 2004-2006 (Box 55, Folder 22)
    - Research on Ike Williams (Box 55, Folder 23)
    - Research on William Carlos Williams (Box 55, Folder 24)
    - Research for tribute to Ruth Stone (Box 55, Folder 25)
    - Sarabande Books royalty statements, 2008-2010 (Box 55, Folder 26)
    - Stern family tree (Box 55, Folder 27)
    - Steven Dunn piece for anthology, 2011-2012 (Box 55, Folder 28)
    - Squaw Valley, 2000 (Box 55, Folder 29)
    - Term paper on Stern, 2008 (Box 55, Folder 30)
    - Term paper on Stern, 2010 (Box 55, Folder 31)
    - "A Tribute to Gerald Stern" by Ed Hirsch, Antioch Review, 2009 (Box 55, Folder 32)
    - T.S. Eliot Talk, New England College, 2008 (Box 55, Folder 33)
    - Virginia Center for the Arts Fellowship, 2007 (Box 55, Folder 34)
- Poems, Essays, etc. for and about Gerald Stern, 1970s-2007; VIII.
  This series includes works for and about Stern written by other authors, including poems, essays, parodies and translations of Stern's work.
  - Poems, 1.
    - Anthologies and general (Box 25, Folder 29)
    - By Author, A-L (Box 25, Folder 30)
    - By Author, M-Z (Box 25, Folder 31)
    - Birthday tributes (Box 25, Folder 32)
  - Essays, Articles, Short Stories, 2.
    - Barron, Jonathan N. (Box 25, Folder 33)
    - Chess, Richard (Box 25, Folder 34)
    - Cochran, Robert (Box 25, Folder 35)
    - De Niord, Chard (Box 25, Folder 36)
    - Drakulic, Slavenka (Box 25, Folder 37)
    - Faerstein, Howard (Box 25, Folder 38)
    - Garber, Frederick (Box 25, Folder 39)
    - Jacobstein, Roy (Box 25, Folder 40)
    - Kaye, Gail (Box 25, Folder 41)
    - Kephart, Beth (Box 25, Folder 42)
    - Locke, Joseph H. (Box 25, Folder 43)
    - Mark, Michael (Box 25, Folder 44)
    - McClung, Dustin (Box 25, Folder 45)
    - McCorkle, James (Box 25, Folder 46)
    - Noel, Karen S. (Box 25, Folder 47)
    - Oness, Chad (Box 25, Folder 48)
    - Oringel, Susan E. (Box 25, Folder 49)
    - Parmet, Harriet L. (Box 25, Folder 50)
    - Pinsker, Sanford (Box 25, Folder 51)
    - Rhodenbaugh, Suzanne (Box 25, Folder 52)
    - Rigsbee, David (Box 25, Folder 53)
    - Robbins, Doren (Box 25, Folder 54)
    - Simpson, Richard (Box 25, Folder 55)
    - Solomon, Mark (Box 25, Folder 56)
    - Spencer, Dayna and Penny Armstrong (Box 25, Folder 57)
    - Stitt, Peter (Box 25, Folder 58)
    - Sysko, L. J. (Box 25, Folder 59)
    - Young, Michael T. (Box 25, Folder 60)
  - Theses, Dissertations, Books, 3.
    - Baumgard, Annette (Box 25, Folder 61)
    - Pletzinger, Thomas (Box 25, Folder 62)
    - Somerville, Jane (Box 25, Folder 63)
  - Reviews, Parodies, Translations, 4.
    - Reviews (Box 25, Folder 64)
    - Parodies (Box 25, Folder 65)
    - Translations (Box 25, Folder 66)
- Manuscripts by Others, 1980-2007; IX.
  This series contains manuscripts written by other writers that were sent to Stern for comment or review. Materials are separated into subseries according to those that contain or do not contain Stern's notes.
  New material was added to this series in 2015.
  - Marked manuscripts with Stern's notes, 1.
    - Anghelaki-Rooke, Katerina (Box 26, Folder 1)
    - Barnstone, Aliki (Box 26, Folder 2)
    - Bluestone, Stephen (Box 26, Folder 3)
    - Goodman, Ron (Box 26, Folder 4)
    - Gregg, Linda (Box 26, Folder 5)
    - Justice, Donald (Box 26, Folder 6)
    - Katrovas, Richard (Box 26, Folder 7)
    - Krygowski, Nancy (Box 26, Folder 8)
    - Mitchell, Susan (Box 26, Folder 9)
    - Pinsker, Sanford (Box 26, Folder 10)
    - Plumly, Stanley (Box 26, Folder 11)
    - Rawson, Eric (Box 26, Folder 12)
    - Revell, Donald (Box 26, Folder 13)
    - South, Patrick (Box 26, Folder 14)
    - Udall, Jay (Box 26, Folder 15)
    - Waldor, Peter (Box 26, Folder 16)
    - Wallach, Yona (Box 26, Folder 17)
    - Wilt, K.V. (Box 26, Folder 18)
  - Unmarked manuscripts, 3.
    - Assorted poems (Box 26, Folder 19)
    - Barnstone, Willis (Box 26, Folder 20)
    - Barron, Jonathan N. (Box 26, Folder 21)
    - Dana, Robert (Box 26, Folder 22)
    - Daniels, Jim (Box 26, Folder 23)
    - Derracote, Toi (Box 26, Folder 24)
    - Desht, Martin (Box 26, Folder 25)
    - Friedman, Jeff and Nati Zohar (Box 26, Folder 26)
    - Garland, Max (Box 26, Folder 27)
    - Goldberg, Barbara (Box 27, Folder 1)
    - Harter, Penny (Box 27, Folder 2)
    - Hoagland, Tony (Box 27, Folder 3)
    - Johnson, J. Chester (Box 27, Folder 4)
    - Joly, Odile (Box 27, Folder 5)
    - Keller, Christopher (Box 27, Folder 6)
    - Keplinger, David (Box 27, Folder 7)
    - Lee, Li-Young (Box 27, Folder 8)
    - Mauch, Matthew D. (Box 27, Folder 9)
    - Millen, Jane (Box 27, Folder 10)
    - Moss, Stanley (Box 27, Folder 11)
    - Moss, Stanley (Box 27, Folder 12)
    - Oresick, Peter (Box 27, Folder 13)
    - Pacernick, Gary (Box 27, Folder 14)
    - Purpura, Lia (Box 27, Folder 15)
    - Robbins, Doren (Box 27, Folder 16)
    - Thomas, Abigail (Box 27, Folder 17)
    - Williams, C.K. (Box 27, Folder 18)
    - Zagajewski, Adam (Box 27, Folder 19)
    - Zisquit, Linda Stern (Box 27, Folder 20)
  - 2015 Addition, 4.
    - Marked manuscripts with Stern's notes
      - Barbarese, Joe, Various Writings (Box 55, Folder 35)
      - Bauer, Curtis, The Real Cause for Your Absence (Box 55, Folder 36)
      - Ciceran, Tristan (Box 55, Folder 37)
      - Daniels, Kelly, The Big Speech (Box 55, Folder 38)
      - Desht, Martin, Various Chapters of Manuscript, 2011 (Box 55, Folder 39)
      - Friedman, Jeff, 2009 (Box 55, Folder 40)
      - Glassman, Naomi, Adolf und Gertrud (Box 55, Folder 41)
      - Goodrich, Christopher (Box 55, Folder 42)
      - Greenberg, Alex, Piece on Allen Ginsberg (Box 55, Folder 43)
      - Hoffman, Adina (Box 55, Folder 44-45)
      - Howell, Rebecca, Translation of Amal al-Jubouri's, "Hagar Before the Occupation (Box 55, Folder 46)
      - Lipton, Ror, 2011 (Box 55, Folder 47)
      - Long, Doc, 2009 (Box 55, Folder 48)
      - Loughran, Michael (Box 55, Folder 49)
      - Moscaliuc, Mihaela (Box 55, Folder 50)
      - Ostriker, Alicia, 2008 (Box 55, Folder 51)
      - Ras, Barbara (Box 55, Folder 52)
      - Revell, Donald, Tantivy (Box 55, Folder 53)
      - Robbins, Doren, 2010 (Box 55, Folder 54)
      - Ruebner, Tuvia (Box 55, Folder 55)
      - Sadoff, Ira (Box 55, Folder 56)
      - Schwartz, Howard, 2008 (Box 56, Folder 1)
      - Schwartz, Lynn (Box 56, Folder 2)
      - Schwartz, Lynne, See You in the Dark (Box 56, Folder 3)
      - Shmueli, Ilana, Drafting a Life (Box 56, Folder 4)
      - Swir, Anna, Various Poems (Box 56, Folder 5)
      - Unknown Author, Various Poems (Box 56, Folder 6)
      - Waldor, Peter, The County Executives (Box 56, Folder 7)
      - Watel, Lauren (Box 56, Folder 8)
      - Watson, Ellen (Box 56, Folder 9)
    - Unmarked manuscripts
      - Aaron, Chester (Box 56, Folder 10-11)
      - Asekoff, L.S. (Box 56, Folder 12)
      - Barbarese, J.T., Various Essays (Box 56, Folder 13)
      - Barnstone, Willis, Dante on the Road (Box 56, Folder 14)
      - Barnstone, Willis, Dawn Cafe in Paris (Box 56, Folder 15)
      - Barnstone, Willis, Dreaming in Chinese (Box 56, Folder 16)
      - Barnstone, Willis, The Fate of the Babylonians (Box 56, Folder 17)
      - Barnstone, Willis, Hope Dangles from Eternity: Poems with Drawings for Ruth Stone (Box 56, Folder 18)
      - Barnstone, Willis, A Night in the Bordello (Box 56, Folder 19)
      - Barnstone, Willis, A Swan Over Manhattan (Box 56, Folder 20-21)
      - Barnstone, Willis, Translation of Dante's Inferno, 2008 (Box 56, Folder 22)
      - Barnstone, Willis, Translation of The Restored New Testament (Box 56, Folder 23-24)
      - Barnstone, Willis, With Pancho Villa On the Road Encountering Poets, TB and Mermaids (Box 56, Folder 25)
      - Bathanti, Joseph (Box 56, Folder 26)
      - Baumel, Judith (Box 56, Folder 27)
      - Behn, Robin (Box 56, Folder 28)
      - Bertolino, Jim (Box 56, Folder 29)
      - Bourne, John Setliffe (Box 56, Folder 30)
      - Boutelle, Annie (Box 56, Folder 31)
      - Boyle, Anita, Whenever the Sun (Box 56, Folder 32)
      - Brasfield, James (Box 56, Folder 33)
      - Campion, Peter (Box 56, Folder 34)
      - Cohen, Andrea (Box 56, Folder 35)
      - Dunn, Stephen (Box 56, Folder 36)
      - Elliot, Wende, The First Half: Poetry from Age 17 to 39 (Box 56, Folder 38)
      - Eklund, George (Box 56, Folder 37)
      - Elliot, Wende, 2009 (Box 56, Folder 39)
      - Finkelstein, Norman, The Sacred and the Real in The Tablets of Armand Schwerner" (Box 56, Folder 40)
      - Friebert, Stuart, 2008 (Box 56, Folder 41)
      - Friedman, Jeff, Birthday (Box 56, Folder 42)
      - Gaspar, Frank (Box 56, Folder 43)
      - Goldbarth, Albert, Everybody's Nickname (Box 57, Folder 1)
      - Golub, Deborah (Box 57, Folder 2)
      - Hand, Monica (Box 57, Folder 3)
      - Harris, Daniel and Adam Shechter (Box 57, Folder 4)
      - Horn, Bernard (Box 57, Folder 5)
      - Johnson, J. Chester, For Conduct and Innocents (In Memory of Dietrich Bonhoeffer), 2010 (Box 57, Folder 6)
      - Kasdorf, Julia, Poetry in America, 2011 (Box 57, Folder 7)
      - Katrovas, Richard, The Magic Book: Why I Thought Publishing a Book Would Change Everything, 2010 (Box 57, Folder 8)
      - Katrovas, Richard (Box 57, Folder 9)
      - Kenny, Adele (Box 57, Folder 10)
      - Kuhn, H. Danielle, Bertolino, Bertolino (Box 57, Folder 11)
      - Larkin, Joan, Brother Dust (Box 57, Folder 12)
      - Levin, Lynn, 2008 (Box 57, Folder 13)
      - Liebrecht, Savyon (Box 57, Folder 14)
      - Logghe, Joan, The Last Streetcar (Box 57, Folder 15)
      - Lowenthal, Rodger, Various Poems (Box 57, Folder 16)
      - Lucas, Terry, The Gate, 2008 (Box 57, Folder 17)
      - Major, Clarence (Box 57, Folder 18)
      - Marmer, Jake, Jazz Talmud, 2011 (Box 57, Folder 19)
      - Marshall, Jack, 2008 (Box 57, Folder 20)
      - Martin, Helbert, 2011 (Box 57, Folder 21)
      - Moscaliuc, Mihaela, Various Poems (Box 57, Folder 22)
      - Moses, Emmanuel (Translated by Marilyn Hack) (Box 57, Folder 23)
      - Olson, Christina, Various Poems (Box 57, Folder 24)
      - Perry, Carole Elizabeth, Night Work (Box 57, Folder 25)
      - Past, Melodie (Box 57, Folder 26)
      - Rackin, Ethel (Box 57, Folder 27)
      - Richards, Peter (Box 57, Folder 28)
      - Robbins, Doren (Box 57, Folder 29)
      - Roffman, Rosaly DeMaios (Box 57, Folder 30)
      - Rubber Side Down, anthology edited by Jose Gouveia, 2008 (Box 57, Folder 31)
      - Rudden, John, 1996 (Box 57, Folder 32)
      - Shmueli, Ilana, "Zwischen Dem Jetzt und Dem Jetzt" (Box 57, Folder 33)
      - Schwartz, Mimi, Traveling with J Street to Israel, the West Bank, and Jordan (Box 57, Folder 34)
      - Udall, Jay (Box 57, Folder 35)
      - Unknown Author, Adieu Paris, Bonjour Paris (Box 57, Folder 36)
      - Unknown Author, Chill and Burn Me: The Amazing Sense of Emily Dickinson (Box 57, Folder 37)
      - Unknown Author, Haiku Harvest (Box 57, Folder 38)
      - Unknown Author, In the Hourglass (Box 57, Folder 39)
      - Unknown Author, The Wild Thing Poems (Box 57, Folder 40)
      - Unknown Author, Why Love Resembles a Fruit and Relics (Box 57, Folder 41)
      - Various Authors, Teen Writing Magazine, Summer 'O9 (Box 57, Folder 42)
      - Various Poets, Poems for Peace: Poems by Jewish and Palestinian Poets (Box 57, Folder 43)
      - Vogelsang, Arthur (Box 57, Folder 44)
      - Vogelsang, Arthur, Expedition, 2009 (Box 57, Folder 45)
      - Waldor, Peter (Box 57, Folder 46)
      - Waldor, Peter, The Wilderness Poetry of Wu Xing (Box 57, Folder 47)
      - Waldor, Peter (Box 57, Folder 48)
      - Zisquit, Linda Stern (Box 57, Folder 49)
- Published Works, 1950-2013; X.
  Included in this series are magazines, periodicals, and anthologies that Stern's works or reviews of his work appeared. The series is arranged by type of publication into two subseries: magazines and periodicals and anthologies.
  - Magazines and Periodicals, 1950-2007; 1.
    - 1950-1969 (Box 28, Folder 1)
    - 1974 (Box 28, Folder 2)
    - 1975 (Box 28, Folder 3)
    - 1976 (Box 28, Folder 4)
    - 1977 (Box 28, Folder 5)
    - 1978 (Box 28, Folder 6)
    - 1978 (Box 28, Folder 7)
    - 1979 (Box 28, Folder 8)
    - 1980 (Box 28, Folder 9)
    - 1980 (Box 28, Folder 10)
    - 1981 (Box 29, Folder 1)
    - 1982 (Box 29, Folder 2)
    - 1982 (Box 29, Folder 3)
    - 1983 (Box 29, Folder 4)
    - 1983 (Box 29, Folder 5)
    - 1984 (Box 29, Folder 6)
    - 1984 (Box 29, Folder 7)
    - 1985 (Box 29, Folder 8)
    - 1985 (Box 29, Folder 9)
    - 1986 (Box 30, Folder 1)
    - 1986 (Box 30, Folder 2)
    - 1987 (Box 30, Folder 3)
    - 1987 (Box 30, Folder 4)
    - 1988 (Box 30, Folder 5)
    - 1989 (Box 30, Folder 6)
    - 1990 (Box 30, Folder 7)
    - 1990 (Box 30, Folder 8)
    - 1991 (Box 30, Folder 9)
    - 1992 (Box 31, Folder 1)
    - 1992 (Box 31, Folder 2)
    - 1993 (Box 31, Folder 3)
    - 1993 (Box 31, Folder 4)
    - 1994 (Box 31, Folder 5)
    - 1995 (Box 31, Folder 6)
    - 1995 (Box 31, Folder 7)
    - 1996 (Box 31, Folder 8)
    - 1996 (Box 31, Folder 9)
    - 1997 (Box 32, Folder 1)
    - 1998 (Box 32, Folder 2)
    - 1999 (Box 32, Folder 3)
    - 1999 (Box 32, Folder 4)
    - 2000 (Box 32, Folder 5)
    - 2000 (Box 32, Folder 6)
    - 2001 (Box 32, Folder 7)
    - 2001 (Box 32, Folder 8)
    - 2002 (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - 2002 (Box 33, Folder 2)
    - 2002 (Box 33, Folder 3)
    - 2003 (Box 33, Folder 4)
    - 2003 (Box 33, Folder 5)
    - 2003 (Box 33, Folder 6)
    - 2004 (Box 33, Folder 7)
    - 2004 (Box 33, Folder 8)
    - 2004 (Box 34, Folder 1)
    - 2005 (Box 34, Folder 2)
    - 2005 (Box 34, Folder 3)
    - 2006 (Box 34, Folder 4)
    - 2006 (Box 34, Folder 5)
    - 2007 (Box 34, Folder 6)
    - 2015 Addition, 1978-2013
      - 1978 (Box 58, Folder 1)
      - 1979 (Box 58, Folder 2)
      - 1981 (Box 58, Folder 3)
      - 1982 (Box 58, Folder 4)
      - 1983 (Box 58, Folder 5)
      - 1984 (Box 58, Folder 6)
      - 1986 (Box 58, Folder 7)
      - 1987 (Box 58, Folder 8)
      - 1989 (Box 58, Folder 9)
      - 1992 (Box 58, Folder 10)
      - 1994 (Box 58, Folder 11)
      - 1995 (Box 58, Folder 12)
      - 1996 (Box 58, Folder 13)
      - 1997 (Box 58, Folder 14)
      - 1998 (Box 58, Folder 15)
      - 1999 (Box 58, Folder 16)
      - 2001 (Box 58, Folder 17)
      - 2003 (Box 58, Folder 18-19)
      - 2004 (Box 58, Folder 20)
      - 2005 (Box 58, Folder 21-22)
      - 2006 (Box 58, Folder 23-24)
      - 2007 (Box 58, Folder 25)
      - 2008 (Box 59, Folder 1-3)
      - 2009 (Box 59, Folder 4-5)
      - 2010 (Box 59, Folder 6-7)
      - 2011 (Box 59, Folder 8-9)
      - 2012 (Box 59, Folder 10-11)
      - 2013 (Box 59, Folder 12)
  - Anthologies, 1970-2007; 2.
    - 1970-1979 (Box 35)
    - 1990-1993 (Box 36)
    - 1994-2000 (Box 37)
    - 2001-2007 (Box 38)
    - 2015 Addition, 1983-2013
      - 1983 (Box 59, Folder 13)
      - 1985 (Box 59, Folder 14-15)
      - 1987 (Box 59, Folder 16)
      - 1989 (Box 59, Folder 17)
      - 1991 (Box 59, Folder 18)
      - 1994 (Box 60, Folder 1)
      - 1995 (Box 60, Folder 2)
      - 1996 (Box 60, Folder 3)
      - 1997 (Box 60, Folder 4)
      - 1998 (Box 60, Folder 5)
      - 2000 (Box 60, Folder 6)
      - 2001 (Box 60, Folder 7)
      - 2002 (Box 60, Folder 8)
      - 2003 (Box 60, Folder 9)
      - 2004 (Box 60, Folder 10)
      - 2005 (Box 60, Folder 11-12)
      - 2006 (Box 60, Folder 13)
      - 2007 (Box 61, Folder 1-2)
      - 2008 (Box 61, Folder 3-4)
      - 2009 (Box 61, Folder 5-6)
      - 2010 (Box 61, Folder 7-8)
      - 2011 (Box 61, Folder 9)
      - 2012 (Box 61, Folder 10-11)
      - 2013 (Box 61, Folder 12-13)
- Photographs, 1930-2007; XI.
  This series includes personal photos of Stern and his family and friends, as well as professional author photos and photos of Stern with other well-known poets. It includes some slides and negatives, as well as prints. The series is divided by topic into three subseries, with dates ranging from the 1930s through 2007.
  - Gerald Stern, 1930-2007; 1.
    - 1930-1940 (Box 39, Folder 1)
    - 1940-1950 (Box 39, Folder 2)
    - 1950-1960 (Box 39, Folder 3)
    - 1960-1970 (Box 39, Folder 4)
    - 1970-1980 (Box 39, Folder 5)
    - 1980-1990 (Box 39, Folder 6)
    - 1990-2000 (Box 39, Folder 7)
    - 2000-2007 (Box 39, Folder 8)
    - Trips with JoAnn Buzetta, 1997 (Box 39, Folder 9)
    - Photo Album, 1998-1999 (Box 39, Folder 10)
    - Trip to Poland, 2000 (Box 39, Folder 11)
  - Family and Friends, 1920-2007; 2.
    - Family (Box 40, Folder 1)
    - Family (Box 40, Folder 2)
    - Family (Box 40, Folder 3)
    - Assorted negatives (Box 40, Folder 4)
    - Calendars of Rebecca Martin and family (Box 40, Folder 5)
    - Ida and Harry Stern (Box 40, Folder 6)
    - Ida and Harry Stern (Box 40, Folder 7)
    - Ida and Harry Stern (Box 40, Folder 8)
    - Ida and Harry Stern (Box 40, Folder 9)
    - Friends (Box 40, Folder 10)
    - Oversized photographs (Box 40, Folder 11)
  - Professional Life, 1940-2007; 3.
    - 1940-1950 (Box 41, Folder 1)
    - 1970-1980 (Box 41, Folder 2)
    - 1990-2000 (Box 41, Folder 3)
    - Gerald Stern with other well-known poets (Box 41, Folder 4)
    - Poets of Pennsylvania (Box 41, Folder 5)
    - Landscapes (Box 41, Folder 6)
    - Photos by Kelly Wise (Box 41, Folder 7)
    - Photos by Laverne Clark (Box 41, Folder 8)
    - Photos by Mark Hillringhouse (Box 41, Folder 9)
    - Photos by Jill Krementz (Box 41, Folder 10)
    - Photos by James Baker Hall (Box 41, Folder 11)
    - Photos by Martin Desht (Box 41, Folder 12)
    - Photos by Mark Kane (Box 41, Folder 13)
    - Photos by Kathleen Lynch (Box 41, Folder 14)
    - Photos by David Burrows (Box 41, Folder 15)
    - Photos by Robert Turney (Box 41, Folder 16)
- Media Material, 1970-2007; XII.
  This series contains media material from projects in which Stern was involved and readings he gave of his poetry, as well as interviews and lectures. The series is arranged into four subseries; the first three by type of event, the last by form.
  - Projects, 1.
    - Somerset Community College - The Making of a Poem (Box 42, Folder 1)
    - Watershed Foundation - Poetry on Tape (Box 42, Folder 2)
    - Daniel Lusk - WHYY Broadcast (Box 42, Folder 3)
    - New England College - MFA Poetry Program (Box 42, Folder 4)
    - Interlochen Arts Academy (Box 42, Folder 5)
    - Temple University Paley Library Presents (Box 42, Folder 6)
  - Readings, 2.
    - Reel to Reel Tapes (Box 42, Folder 7)
    - Audiocassettes, 1970s-1980s (Box 43, Folder 1)
    - Audiocassettes, 1990s-2000s (Box 43, Folder 2)